# **Philip George**

London, England +447484188198 philipgeorge.io linkedin.com/in/philipgeorgeio github.com/pg328 Multi-Page CV

## **INTRODUCTION**

I'm Philip George, a full stack software engineer with just under **5 years** of industry experience — starting as hire #6 at **MetaDataWorks** and later helping SMEs like **Dunelm** scale their platforms.

At **MetaDataWorks**, I was the sole front-end developer on a medical-ontology browser for the NHS—running weekly demos with non-technical stakeholders to gather feedback and refine the UI until clinicians embraced it, which led to a £1.2 million, three-year contract. After a promotion, I led the front-end of our flagship **Metadata Browser**, delivering an accessibility overhaul to meet government standards and a full **JavaScript-to-TypeScript** migration to eliminate runtime errors and boost developer productivity.

#### PERFORMANCE HIGHLIGHTS

- Greenfield Search Web-App sold to NHS: Led FE development on SaaS medical ontology browser, enhancing NHS's health data concept management and accessibility. Sold for £1.2M over a 3 year contract.
- Stakeholder Meeting Presentations: Demonstrated new features, contributing to the acquisition of a client contract.
- 10x Performance Optimisation: Tasked with streamlining an organisation wide access control management page, achieved a 1000% decrease in page load time, significantly boosting app performance.
- Usability and Accessibility Lectures: Raised company-wide awareness through presentations, enabling more inclusive
  and user-friendly product design.
- System Architecture and Design I designed and implemented a modernisation strategy by creating architecture diagrams, conducting team talks, and separating work into tickets, leading to the successful modernisation of the platform component, improving functionality and performance.
- JavaScript -> TypeScript Codebase Conversion: Led successful migration from JavaScript to TypeScript, enhancing code
  robustness and maintainability without compromising delivery targets.

#### **EDUCATION**

BSc Mathematics and Computer Science - University of Exeter
 September 2015 — November 2019

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Software Engineer and Founder Forge Software Solutions Limited   London, England	March 2024 – Present
Disperse   London, England	
Full Stack Software Engineer	June 2022 — July 2023 (1 year 2 months)
Dunelm   London, England	
Junior Software Engineer -> Software Engineer	Nov 2019 — Feb 2022 (2 years 4 months)

MetaDataWorks | London, England

### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

Software Engineering | Full Stack Development | Project Leadership | Agile Methodologies | Problem Solving | Cross-Functional Collaboration | Test-Driven Development (TDD) | Continuous Integration & Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) | Technical Writing | Cloud Computing | User Interface Design | Database Management

Languages: TypeScript | Python | SQL | Java | Shell/Bash | JavaScript

**Web Development**: React | Node.js | GraphQL | Django | NGINX | GitHub Actions | Jest | Cypress | Storybook | Spring Framework | Grails | Kibana | Maven | Gradle

Machine Learning: TensorFlow (Keras), NumPy, MatPlotLib, SciPy

DevOps + Cloud: AWS | Docker | Terraform | Serverless

Databases mySQL | MongoDB | SQLite | Postgres | ElasticSearch

Technologies: ECS | S3 | EC2 | Cloudfront | ELB | Serverless | Edge Functions | SNS | SQS